Guide to the Lenore Seroka's "Artists on Site" photographs 1977-1989 PR 478
New-York Historical Society
Lenore Seroka's "Artists on Site" photographs
1977-1989
New-York Historical Society
Seroka, Lenore, 1935-2016
PR 478
6 Linear feet in 12 folders
This collection consists of photographs of noted artists in their studios. The photographs were taken by Lenore Seroka (1935-2016) between 1977-1989.
Arrangement
The photographs are arranged alphabetically by artist name.
Biographical / Historical
Lenore Seroka (1935-2016) was a photographer in Great Neck, New York. Seroka's papers are held by the Archives of American Art.
Access Restrictions
Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Stanley Seroka, 2023.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of portraits of noted artists in their studios. The photographs were taken by Lenore Seroka (1935-2016) between 1977-1989 for her project "Artists on Site." Most are black and white, and some are signed and dated by the photographer. Among the many celebrated artists included are painters Roy Lichtenstein and Keith Haring, sculptors Louise Bourgeois and Judy Pfaff, and installation artists Dan Flavin and Christo.
The artists were identified during processing, and their names appear on the versos. Dates were taken from additional material donated with the collection; however many images are undated.
Artists -- Portraits.; Artists' studios; Portrait photography.; Women photographers.; Photographs.
- Amenoff, Gregory, 1988 (Folder FF 1)
- Andrews, Benny, 1982 (Folder FF 1)
- Anuszkiewicz, Richard, 1984 (Folder FF 1)
- Artschwager, Richard (Folder FF 1)
  Scope and Contents
  2 copies of the same image.
- Barnett, Will, 1977, 1978 (Folder FF 2)
  2 different images.
- Beal, Jack, 1983 (Folder FF 2)
- Bearden, Romare, 1981 (Folder FF 2)
- Bidlo, Mike, 1988 (Folder FF 2)
- Bishop, Isabell (Folder FF 2)
- Bourgeois, Louise (Folder FF 2)
  3 copies of the same image.
- Brooks, James, 1985 (Folder FF 2)
- Burkhardt, Rudy, 1978 (Folder FF 2)
- Cavallon, Giorgio, 1982 (Folder FF 3)
- Chamberlain, John (Folder FF 3)
- Chen Chi, 1984 (Folder FF 3)
- Close, Chuck, 1983 (Folder FF 3)
- Close, Chuck and Ray Johnson, 1983 (Folder FF 3)
- De Creeft, Jose (Folder FF 4)
- De Kooning, Elaine, 1983 (Folder FF 4)
- Estes, Richard, 1982 (Folder FF 4)
- Ferber, Herbert (Folder FF 4)
- Fish, Janet, 1985 (Folder FF 4)
- Flavin, Dan (Folder FF 4)
- Freilicher, Jane, 1982 (Folder FF 4)
- Golub, Leon, 1983 (Folder FF 5)
- Goodnough, Robert, 1982 (Folder FF 5)
- Greene, Balcomb, 1982 (Folder FF 5)
- Gross, Chaim, 1977 (Folder FF 6)
  2 copies of same image.
- Gwathmey, Robert, 1981 (Folder FF 6)
- Halley, Peter, 1989 (Folder FF 6)
- Haring, Keith (Folder FF 6)
- Heliker, John, 1982 (Folder FF 6)
- Hirsch, Joseph, 1977 (Folder FF 6)
- Hirschfeld, Al, 1984 (Folder FF 6)
- Hunt, Bryan, 1988 (Folder FF 6)
- Javacheff, Christo, 1984 (Folder FF 6)
- Kanovitz, Howard, 1986 (Folder FF 7)
- Kass, Deborah, 1989 (Folder FF 7)
- Katz, Alex, 1977 (Folder FF 7)
- Katzen, Lila, 1983 (Folder FF 7)
- Kendrick, Mel, 1989 (Folder FF 7)
- Kitaj, R.B., 1983 (Folder FF 7)
- Kostabi, Mark, 1988 (Folder FF 7)
- Kosuth, Joseph, 1988 (Folder FF 7)
- Krasner, Lee, 1983 (Folder FF 7)
- Krushenick, Nicholas (Folder FF 7)
- Lassaw, Ibram, 1983 (Folder FF 8)
- Levine, David (Folder FF 8)
- Levine, Jack, 1977 (Folder FF 8)
- Levy, Benjamin, 1985 (Folder FF 8)
- Lichtenstein, Roy (Folder FF 8)
- Lipton, Seymour, 1981 (Folder FF 8)
- Longo, Robert, 1989 (Folder FF 8)
- Lucchesi, Bruno, 1982 (Folder FF 8)
- Meyer, Melissa, 1989 (Folder FF 9)
- Mullican, Matt, 1989 (Folder FF 9)
- Neel, Alice, 1983 (Folder FF 9)
- Nesbitt, Lowell, 1982 (Folder FF 9)
- Newman, Arnold, 1983 (Folder FF 9)
- Pearlstein, Philip, 1978 (Folder FF 9)
- Pfaff, Judy, 1988 (Folder FF 9)
- Reisman, Philip, 1977 (Folder FF 10)
- Resika, Paul, 1978 (Folder FF 10)
- Resnick, Milton, 1984 (Folder FF 10)
- Rivers, Larry, 1981 (Folder FF 10)
- Rockbouroe, Dorothea, 1978 (Folder FF 10)
- Rosenquist, James, 1984 (Folder FF 11)
- Scharf, Kenny, 1989 (Folder FF 11)
- Segal, George, 1980 (Folder FF 11)
- Sleigh, Sylvia, 1978 (Folder FF 11)
- Smith, Leon Polk, 1986 (Folder FF 11)
- Soyer, Raphael, 1978 (Folder FF 11)
- Spero, Nancy, 1983 (Folder FF 11)
- Stamos, Theodoros, 1979 (Folder FF 12)
- Stephan, Gary, 1988 (Folder FF 12)
- Stevens, May, 1978 (Folder FF 12)
- Sultan, Donald, 1988 (Folder FF 12)
- Vaisman, Meyer (Folder FF 12)
- Wesselman, Tom, 1978 (Folder FF 12)
- Youngerman, Jack, 1980 (Folder FF 12)
- Miscellaneous (Folder FF 12)
  Additional material donated with the photographs. Includes typed identifying labels, a business card, and a press release for an exhibit of Seroka's photos at Great Neck House.